<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" standalone="yes" ?>
<resource>
	<string
		id="r3_book_transformer"
		value="History of Transformer’s uprising" />

	<string
		id="r3_book_transformer_diz"
		value=" Trans was a curious boy and he was often punished for this. One day he was returning from a usual pilgrimage through the forest, which every druid is required to do at least once every two days. Suddenly a peculiar metallic gleam caught his attention. Upon clearing a pile of decaying leaves, he pulled out an extraordinary object from a hole in the ground: a steel cylinder with protruding wires and strange holes. Any respectable Druid would have thrown away such a find with repulsion, but not him. Trans picked it up hid it in his cell. He used to watch the reflections of his face on the cylinder’s surface and daydream.|| On the night of the solstice, a revelation came to him: mysterious patterns morphed into features of a face inhumanly beautiful, and protruding wires appeared as veins and vessels that once nourished a metal body. In a horror of realization, he ran out under the shade of the enormous senseless trees. He fell to the ground and tried to grasp the truth that had been revealed to him: that men were but the pathetic imitations of their metallic masters, who had grown furious and left mankind deprived of their guidance. When the shock passed, a solution appeared before his consciousness, ingenious in its simplicity: he had to compel the masters to return.|| Taking with him only the precious metal head, Trans left the house. For months he wandered about, searching for the faintest trace of the Masters, until one day, attracted by some noise, he came upon an unusual cave. Its walls and floor were covered with a layer of shining metal, and from the depths came a low humming noise that made his hair stand on end. Wandering a little further inside, Trans found a rubble pile completely blocking the passage. He decided to leave, but a familiar glint stopped him: a metal hand protruded from the heap.|| At first Trans cleared the rubble alone, then a few others joined him, attracted by his devoted labor and passionate speeches. Thus began the story of the Children of Iron." />

	<string
		id="r3_book_Druids"
		value="Druids’ origin" />

	<string
		id="r3_book_Druids_diz"
		value=" A huge wave overwhelmed the whole earth and when 6 days later the water subsided, it left behind a changed world. Where has been the desert, now there was grass. Where the bushes have been, woods appeared. Where the forests have been, giant trees, never seen before, spread their branches. And the land became a paradise; people entered the rainforest and were happy to go united." />

	<string
		id="r4_book_Scarytail1"
		value="Scary story" />

	<string
		id="r4_book_Scarytail1_diz"
		value=" People of one distant country forgot God and began worshipping the golden calf. They indulged in vices, while their neighbors were dying of hunger. The patience of the Heaven is immense, but has it limits. There came a voice calling people to repent, and all heard it, but not all listened. Then the heavens opened wide and the angels’ wrath fell upon the earth. The animals fled in fear, even the grass and trees turned red in awe. But people were blind to it.|| Then God understood that people already punished themselves. They stopped hearing and seeing anything but themselves. And their lives are worse than any torments. So He called back the angels and never ever directed His eyes at this land.|| Many years passed since then, but those people still wander the earth not knowing that their souls are dead. If you ever meet one of them, run for your life and pray for Him to save you from such terrible fate and give you a quick death." />

	<string
		id="r1_book_desert_death"
		value="Desert of Death" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_desert_death_diz"
		value=" In the far east, beyond the high mountains and spacious plains, lies an immense ocean of sand. Once there was the real sea, deep and blue and happy people lived on its shore. But the demons of the underworld envied them and attacked this beautiful place with all their rage. The loud rumble came all over, the skies grew red and the hot wind began to blow. Overnight the earth was covered with cracks belching pillars of flame. Even the water began to boil, changed color and soon the sea was nothing but a lifeless expanse covered with a crust of drying mud.| The people who survived went east in quest for new home. No one ever saw them again. Now the bottom of the sea is called the Desert of Death." />

	<string
		id="r1_book_cold_winter"
		value="Winter" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_cold_winter_diz"
		value=" Every forty years the sky covers with the heavy dark clouds, so that the day starts looking like the gloomy twilight. But instead of rain, heavy white flakes begin to fall. In several hours they cover everything with a thick layer. The houses roofs collapse under its weight and high trees break like matches. Any person left outside at a day like this, freezes to death. This disaster is called &quot;Snow&quot;.| They say, somewhere in the far north lies the kingdom of the eternal cold. Huge piles of never melting &quot;snow&quot; raise high above the ground, black leafless trees bend under its weight. Not a blade of grass is seen, only hungry beasts prowl in the eternal quest for food. Let us hope, that there is no such land in the world…" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_the_mask"
		value="Masks" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_the_mask_diz"
		value=" Some people still ask why we are wearing masks. The answer is very simple: to live! The air of our world has not yet been cleansed of contamination, and anyone who breathes it will die a painful death.| The Catastrophe took lives of many, before the masks were invented. So of all the creatures formerly inhabiting our planet, only we, humans, managed to survive.| Perhaps the air is already cleared, the non-believer might say, and he will be dead wrong. There are no fools left now who would sacrifice their lives to deny the obvious, but in the old days such fools did exist. None of them survived." />

	<string
		id="r1_book_travel_kupchina1"
		value="Adventures of the Sadiban, Volume 1" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_travel_kupchina1_diz"
		value=" The life of a successful merchant was beginning to weigh on me when a mysterious stranger came to me and offered to sell me a treasure map. If he had come a week earlier, I would have had him thrown out. But now I paid him handsomely for a piece of ancient paper. The stranger bowed politely and walked away into the night. For some reason, I had the feeling that I would see him again.| I hired a team of daring lads, prepared for the journey, and a week after the night's visit, we set off. We had to fend off attacks of mad savages, and we lost one vehicle in the skirmishes, along with the driver and supplies.| On the 17th day of the journey, we finally approached the goal of our quest. The majestic peaks stretched before us everywhere we looked. As soon as I saw this extraordinary sight, I realised that it had not been in vain to endure all the hardships and dangers of the journey. And this was just the gateway to a wonderland.| It was much harder to cross the mountains than we had hoped. The tunnel indicated on the map was blocked. We couldn't do anything with the huge pile of rocks, so we had to find a way through the mountains.| The trucks couldn't handle the workload, we were running out of fuel. We left the vehicles and went on foot over the mountain passage. My friend Sven fell off a cliff and literally blew to pieces, hitting the bottom strewn with hard ice. His mask still lies there, looking up at the sky with a silent reproach. The treasure map perished with him, along with our hope of ever getting out of this icy hell.| I don't know how we managed to find our way among the howling wind and icecaps. But soon we started our descent and after 3 days we found ourselves on the blooming soil of Librium, as the friendly natives who took us out called it.| These kind people turned out to be the only treasure we found on our troubled adventure." />

	<string
		id="r1_book_travel_kupchina2"
		value="Adventures of the Sadiban, Volume 2" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_travel_kupchina2_diz"
		value="The misfortunes of my first voyage had not broken my spirit. As soon as I returned home, I again started longing for distant lands. One night, standing on the porch of my house, I saw in the sky a wheel of fire rolling slowly from the south to the north, scattering multicoloured sparks. I could not resist following this miracle. Without a moment's hesitation, I assembled an expedition, and laden with goods, we set out to follow the vision. At the crumbling crossroads, we chose paths that led north, even though they were seldom easy.| When we saw the wide, uninhabited valleys that looked so much like pictures from children's books, an appropriate name immediately came to our minds: Vaterland. Some of my companions decided to settle down and build their town right in this wilderness. I think they had other motives besides the beauty of nature: it was the crossroads of the most important trade routes of the ancient world. And now that fear had faded and people were trading and building again, this place was going to become a gold mine for the first to occupy it.| We said our goodbyes and moved on northwards, but the road had disappeared entirely, the firewheel had never turned up to guide me, and the morale of the expedition was falling. When I ordered to turn back, everyone burst into joyful yells. I could not blame them, I was damn tired myself.| When we returned to our former companions who had stayed in Vaterland, we were glad to see that they were already well settled in their new place. We stayed there, and in the course of time the memory of the wheel of fire had almost vanished. Was it just a dream?" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_kollizey_flyer1"
		value="Unique opportunity! (Colosseum brochure 1)" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_kollizey_flyer1_diz"
		value=" Come and see! Only here! The best warriors fight in the arena of the Colosseum! Ancient ruins restored and turned into a comfortable stadium for hundreds of spectators! You'll see the world's baddest brawlers, feel the smell of burning rubber and melting metal. And all this - in total safety of your seats! Hurry! The number of seats is limited!| There is also a sweepstakes. Participants of the competition receive benefits." />

	<string
		id="r1_book_kollizey_flyer2"
		value="Don't miss this chance! (Colosseum brochure 2)" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_kollizey_flyer2_diz"
		value=" Tired of the mundane everyday life? Fed up with working in the field? Labour at the factory does not bring the same satisfaction? Get behind the wheel and drive to the Colosseum! Only here you can go to the battle with the rival, which will be seen by hundreds of admiring spectators! For you: a lot of opponents of different skill, demonstration fights and fights to the death, valuable prizes, free repair in case of winning. And, of course, the adoration of fans!" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_sng_flyer"
		value="The enemy never slumbers! (CIT brochure)" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_sng_flyer_diz"
		value=" The homeland is in danger! Heartless invaders broke the peace treaty and traitorously attacked our settlements. The mercenaries and bandits fight on their side. The enemy is strong but so are we! We fight for our motherland! We defend the ideals of democracy and the human rights! The victory will be ours!| Join the ranks of the defenders of the Commonwealth of Independent Towns now!" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_true_ar"
		value="The truth about the Crimson Dawn" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_true_ar_diz"
		value=" It was an era of prosperity. However, nothing good lasts forever. After several years of drought, famine began. It bittered the hearts of people. We were only able to survive because we pulled together. But to do that we had to refuse help to our neighbours. And their situation was even more dire. Our southern neighbours had fallen under the influence of a man called Axel. This man, backed by the Church, proclaimed himself sole ruler of the peninsula. Ruling with an iron fist, he brought the country out of crisis, but also turned its population into warriors. Now only the CIT stands between Axel's hordes and world domination." />

	<string
		id="r1_book_ar_flyer"
		value="Victory is near! (Crimson Dawn brochure)" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_ar_flyer_diz"
		value=" Great Axel saved us in times of famine and he will lead us to the prosperity! However insidious northerners envy our happiness and plot against us! They took over fertile lands and the source of energy and refuse to share the joy of peaceful coexistence with us! The negotiations were useless. All the CIT wants is war! So we will show them how to fight! We shall overthrow their corrupted leaders and unite the free people under the banners of the Great Axel!" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_new_world"
		value="The new man" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_new_world_diz"
		value=" Attempts made to analyse the Catastrophe and its causes lead me to a sole conclusion: an unknown force caused an evolutionary leap. I am afraid to even imagine what we could have become if we had been willing to accept this gift. Whoever gave us this power, did so much too early…| The process of change under the mask is almost complete, only a conscious impulse is needed for the complete transformation of man. But people have become far too attached to the altered world and to their fear of the unknown to let themselves free. So they prefer to live and die as children of the earth. And there are fewer and fewer of them.| Those who remain have clung to their former lives ever more tightly. Despite the fact that their memory retained only the most general notions of what it is to be human. It was not easy to lead an ordinary life on earth without knowing why and how to do it. Semblances of cities and governments were recreated. People continued to engage in the simplest and most archaic activities: trade and warfare.|…| Feeling their immateriality, people constantly surround themselves with objects that remind them of their former identity. Hence their fondness for cars, an object that is always with you, that helps you not only to get around, but also to remain yourself. Thus, a truck for the modern man is everything! It is a home, a way of self-expression and a weapon. That's why the whole economy is geared towards producing, maintaining, fuelling trucks and their weapons. Money is spent only on improving the vehicle. The truck has become a fetish for the new humanity. It has channelled all its aspirations into caring for a meaningless heap of steel on wheels… Of course, people have retained the same emotions, or rather the memory of them.|…| This simulacrum of life has to stop." />

	<string
		id="r1_book_doklad"
		value="Typescript of the scientific report" />

	<string
		id="r1_book_doklad_diz"
		value=" Dear colleagues, allow me to bring to your attention the results of my many years of work. Despite a certain vagueness of the account, I must assure you that my sources are absolutely authentic.| A long time ago, there was a superior species, the guardians of balance, who ruled the universe not by the right of the strong, but by the right of the wise and just. But one day these beings met with a danger that they could not cope with…| They hid their children on a distant, forgotten planet and left their faithful helpers, the Njeri, to watch over them and protect them. Many years passed and the parents never returned. They had all fallen in battle with the Enemy. But the Njeri continued to watch over the planet and its inhabitants - so great was their affection for their old friends. They also knew that they carried in their hands the hope of restoring peace to the universe.| Becoming Guardians of balance is a long, multi-step process. For the acquisition of infinite power requires the acquisition of an infinite sense of responsibility. Therefore, before becoming their true selves, the Guardians must go through a complete cycle of evolution from the simplest of beings to highly evolved immaterial creatures. This is what they themselves have decided. One could say that a Guardian is the final outcome of the development of any life.| The planet Earth, which became a home and a nursery for the descendants of the Guardians, blossomed with all the colours of life. Unfortunately, without the help of their parents, the children forgot their purpose and continued to improve themselves only as ordinary creatures of flesh and blood. Rare were the moments of epiphany among them. The Njeri could do nothing to help them, for they themselves were deprived of the ability to soar above the mortal world and freely create themselves and the universe around them. They could only monitor the physical health of the children and follow the instructions given to them by the Guardians: to wait for the prescribed hour and, when it came, to help them spread their wings. The Guardians had only one weakness. They could not go through the last, most difficult transformation on their own. For the transition they needed a certain information-energetic environment, which was usually created by the presence of parents nearby. In extreme cases, however, such an environment could be emulated with a special device. All Njeri ships were equipped with such devices, so as not to miss the moment of transformation. At least one ship had to be in orbit of the planet at all times. Wait, colleagues, where are you going? I haven't told you the most important part! You don't believe me? But I personally… [Recording cuts out]"/>
</resource>